<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on NIH Data Science SIG</title>
    <link>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on NIH Data Science SIG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Computational and Experimental Biology in HIV Research</title>
      <link>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/03/29/linking-computational-and-experimental-biology-in-hiv-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</author>
      <guid>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/03/29/linking-computational-and-experimental-biology-in-hiv-research/</guid>
      <description>Location: Frederick National Laboratory for Cancer Research
Bldg 549 Scientific Library
549 Sultan St, Frederick, MD 21702
Main Conference Room
No Registration is Required
Schedule Thursday, March 29th    Time Presenter Talk Title     9:00 – 9:30 Brandon Keele, Ph.D. - AIDS and Cancer Virus Program Welcome and Introduction   9:30 – 10:30 Alan Perelson, Ph.D. Los Alamos National Laboratory Plenary Talk: Modeling interactions between HIV/SIV and antibodies and effector cells   10:30 – 11:00 COFFEE BREAK    11:00 – 11:30 Christine Fennessey, Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating from Chemistry to Clinic with Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/03/07/translating-from-chemistry-to-clinic-with-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</author>
      <guid>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/03/07/translating-from-chemistry-to-clinic-with-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>NLM Informatics and Data Science Lecture Series
Abstract: Many medicines become toxic only after bioactivation by metabolizing enzymes. Often, metabolic enzymes transformed them into chemically reactive species, which subsequently conjugate to proteins and cause adverse events. For example, carbamazepine is epoxidized by P450 enzymes in the liver, but then conjugates to proteins, causing Stevens Johnson Syndrome in some patients. The most difficult to predict drug reactions, idiosyncratic adverse drug reactions, often depend on bioactivation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing massive genomics datasets using Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/26/analyzing-massive-genomics-datasets-using-apache-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</author>
      <guid>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/26/analyzing-massive-genomics-datasets-using-apache-spark/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Powered by the continuous decrease of the cost of sequencing a single human genome, &amp;laquo;big data&amp;raquo; sequencing studies (&amp;gt;10,000 sample) are becoming common in both industrial and research settings. Recently, several prominent libraries like GATK4, ADAM, and Hail have used Apache Spark to achieve this goal. Apache Spark is a &amp;laquo;map-reduce&amp;raquo;-like system that allows code written in Scala, Java, Python, R, or SQL to be run in parallel across a cluster with hundreds to thousands of cores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-day NIH Data Science Learning and Testing Hackathon (application required)</title>
      <link>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/23/one-day-nih-data-science-learning-and-testing-hackathon-application-required/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</author>
      <guid>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/23/one-day-nih-data-science-learning-and-testing-hackathon-application-required/</guid>
      <description>About the event The NIH will host a Learning and Testing Data Science hackathon on February 23rd, 2018 on the main campus in Bethesda, MD. Learners will test alpha and beta code that have been generated in full, collaborative development hackathons for a wide range of scientific problems, including general bioinformatics and genomic analyses in addition to text, image, and sequence processing. This event is for researchers who are in the early stages of their data science journey, including students and postdocs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CANDLE Two-day Big Data Workshop</title>
      <link>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/21/candle-two-day-big-data-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</author>
      <guid>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/21/candle-two-day-big-data-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Do you have massive amounts of data? Have you heard about deep learning and machine learning and would like to learn to utilize these approaches in your research? Join us for the CANDLE workshop to explore one of many ways high-performance computing can be used to tackle cancer research challenges and advance precision oncology.
The CANDLE workshop is a collaboration between the NCI Center for Biomedical Informatics and Information Technology, Frederick National Laboratory for Cancer Research, and the Department of Energy’s (DOE) National Laboratories (Argonne, Lawrence Livermore, Los Alamos, and Oak Ridge).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Double Header! Data Science SIG Symposium: Resolving hidden structural variations using long-read sequencing AND Biowulf Seminar Series: How to build a dog in 2,392,715,236 simple steps</title>
      <link>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/21/data-science-double-header-data-science-sig-symposium-resolving-hidden-structural-variations-using-long-read-sequencing-and-biowulf-seminar-series-how-to-build-a-dog-in-2392715236-simple-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</author>
      <guid>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/21/data-science-double-header-data-science-sig-symposium-resolving-hidden-structural-variations-using-long-read-sequencing-and-biowulf-seminar-series-how-to-build-a-dog-in-2392715236-simple-steps/</guid>
      <description>In this Data Science Double Header, PacBio&amp;rsquo;s Steve Turner will speak about resolving structural variants, then NHGRI&amp;rsquo;s Heidi Parker will speak about assembling dog genomes on biowulf!
The Biowulf seminar series continues with talks by Biowulf users. The first such seminar features Heidi Parker, the Senior Staff Scientist for the Dog Genome Project at NHGRI.
Please contact staff@hpc.nih.gov with any questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haloarchaeal genomics and the origin of the prokaryotic ‘species’</title>
      <link>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/08/haloarchaeal-genomics-and-the-origin-of-the-prokaryotic-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</author>
      <guid>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/08/haloarchaeal-genomics-and-the-origin-of-the-prokaryotic-species/</guid>
      <description>About the speaker: Dr. DasSarma is a pioneering microbiologist well-known for his contributions to the genomics, molecular biology, and biotechnology of Archaea and the field of Astrobiology. Prior to joining the Institute of Marine and Environmental Technology, University of Maryland School of Medicine, he was a Professor in the University of Massachusetts Amherst and the University of Maryland Biotechnology Institute. He has published over 125 scientific papers over his career and mentored many students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioinformatics Special Interest Group 2017 Pi Day Winner Seminars</title>
      <link>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/01/bioinformatics-special-interest-group-2017-pi-day-winner-seminars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</author>
      <guid>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/01/bioinformatics-special-interest-group-2017-pi-day-winner-seminars/</guid>
      <description>Bioinformatics SIG Pi Day Winners Seminars
Titles:
 “Balancing Modernity, Stability, and Reproducibility in Computational Analyses” “Striking Back at Alzheimer’s Disease: From Bioenergetics to Behavioral Modification”  Presenters:
 David Hoover and Afif Elghraoui, CIT, Helix Group, Robert Pawlosky, NIAAA  Thursday, February 1st, 3 pm
Location: Building 50, room 1328/1334 (rear)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromosome Conformation in Context</title>
      <link>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/01/chromosome-conformation-in-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</author>
      <guid>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/02/01/chromosome-conformation-in-context/</guid>
      <description>title: NIDDK Seminar – Chromosome Conformation in Context
Presenter: Dr. James Taylor, Ralph S. O’Connor Associate Professor of Biology and Computer Science, Johns Hopkins
When: Thursday, Feb 1st, 11 am
Where: Building 50, Rm 1328</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning in Brain Imaging and Neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/01/30/machine-learning-in-brain-imaging-and-neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seandavi@gmail.com (NIH Data Science SIG)</author>
      <guid>https://nihdatasciencesig.github.io/event/2018/01/30/machine-learning-in-brain-imaging-and-neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Deep learning has arisen around 2006 as a renewal of neural networks research allowing such models to have more layers. It is leading the charge of a renewal of AI both inside and outside academia, with billions of dollars being invested and expected fallouts in the trillions by 2030. Theoretical investigations have shown that functions obtained as deep compositions of simpler functions (which includes both deep and recurrent nets) can express highly varying functions (with many ups and downs and different input regions that can be distinguished) much more efficiently (with fewer parameters) than otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>